Guide to the William Van Duyn Tobacco Advertisement Collection
Medical Historical Library, Harvey Cushing / John Hay Whitney Medical Library
- Oversize, Series II
  - Magazine advertisements for cigarettes by brand, Subseries 1
    - R. J. Reynolds: Kamel Red, Kamel Menthe; Moonlight Tobacco Co., 1996-1999 (Box 164)
      Kamel Red: "Established-1913; Re-established-1996."
    - R. J. Reynolds: Salem, 1957-1991 (Box 165)
    - R .J. Reynolds: Salem, 1998-2000 (Box 166)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 1954-1993 (Box 167)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 1996-1998 (Box 168)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Winston, 1998-1999 (Box 169)
    - R. J. Reynolds: Doral, Vantage, Now, Bright, Tempo, Brandon, Real, More, Sterling, Magna, 1962-1999 (Box 170)
    - Other companies and brands, 1934-1999 (Box 171)
      Axton-Fisher Tobacco Company: Spud, Fleetwood; Riggio Tobacco Company: Regent; United States Tobacco Co.: King Sano; Natural Tobacco Company: Natural American Spirit; Kretek International: Djarum.
    - United Kingdom brands, mostly 1960s-1970s (Box 172)
      Sotheby, Slim Kings, Embassy, Consulate, Rothmans, Sobranie, du Maurier, Craven, Dunhill, St. Moritz, Peter Stuyvesant, Lambert & Butler.
    - United Kingdom brands, 1960s-1990s (Box 173)
      Benson and Hedges, Silk Cut. Includes government anti-smoking advertisements.
    - International brands, 1960s-1990s (Box 174)
      Winston, Camel, Chesterfield, Lucky Strike, L&M, Pall Mall, Benson and Hedges, Pierre Cardin, Stuyvesant, Player's P&S, Craven "A", Dunhill, Gauloises, Kings, Kent, Astor, HB, Lord, West, Philip Morris, R1, Fortuna, SM, Nobel, and others. English, French, German, Spanish, Russian, Greek and other languages. Some Winston sponsorship of music and Camel merchandising of "adventure boots."
  - Other tobacco advertisements, Subseries 2
    - Tobacco company advertising to retailers, mostly 1990s (Box 175)
    - Smoking accessories advertisements, 1930s-1990s (Box 176)
      Lighters including Ronson, A.S.R, Zippo, Casco, and cigarette holder Dunhill De-Nicotea (some advertisements featuring doctors). Some advertisements for loose tobacco and rolling papers at the end.
    - Other tobacco products: cigarillos, cigars, pipe tobacco, chewing tobacco, snuff, 1913-1997 (Box 177)
    - Marlboro listings of nightspots, 1998-1999 (Box 178)
      Attractively designed full or double-page advertisements featuring the Marlboro name or M logo and information on local nightspots.. Many pages are from the New York Press and the Village Voice. Some are from the New Haven Advocate
    - Camel-sponsored local newspaper guides to urban nightlife, 1997-1999 (Box 179)
      From the Village Voice.
    - Smoking, cars, and racing, 1940s-1990s (Box 180)
      Smoking in advertisements for cars; cigarette brand advertisements on racing cars.
    - Cigarettes in magazine advertisements for other products, mostly 1930s-1960s (Box 181)
      Drinks, clothing, toothpaste, cosmetics, food, insurance, etc.
    - Magazine covers, movie advertisements, and songs, 1930-1999 (Box 182)
      Magazine covers showing people smoking from Life, Saturday Evening Post, New York Press, Village Voice, and others; movie advertisements showing someone smoking; original sheet music (8 items and 2 duplicates) that features someone on the cover smoking, or a song that has some relation to cigarettes. Of special note is the sheet music for "Stormy Weather" (1933), first sung by Ethel Waters at the Cotton Club.
    - Images of people smoking, 1940s-1990s (Box 183)
  - Anti-Smoking and Tobacco Politics, Subseries 3
    - Anti-smoking advertisements, 1957-1999 (Box 184)
      Anti-smoking articles, advertisements, cartoons, class-action suit information. Among organizations represented are AdBusters, the Food and Drug Administration, and the National Cancer Society Great American Smokeout. Includes British and Spanish articles from Select Magazine and Quo. The last part of the binder contains advertisements for smoking cessation products including Bantron, Health Information Center (Passabecq method), Habitrol, NicoDerm, Nicorette, Nicotrol, CigArrest, and Zyban.
    - "Pro-tobacco articles", 1936-1999 (Box 185)
      Fortune articles on Philip Morris, Lucky Strike, Reynolds Tobacco, and by the advertising agency that that created Kool and the Kool penguin (original, not photocopies), 1930s; Outdoor Advertising Company marketing of billboards; miscellaneous articles and images showing smoking in a good light; response advertisements by tobacco companies to the litigation of the 1990s; and articles from the American Lawyer (1999), on what tobacco companies gained from the tobacco settlement of 1997.
    - Newspaper articles on tobacco politics, 1935, 1957, 1997-2000 (Box 186)
      Newspaper articles on the tobacco industry settlement of 1997, teen smoking, and other tobacco issues. Binder begins with "Alcohol and Tobacco," Fortune (1935), and "New Cigaret-Cancer Link" (1957).
    - Convenience stores and cigarettes, 1996-2001 (Box 187)
      Articles from Convenience Store News on tobacco issues, including not selling cigarettes to minors.